export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Fixatives are usually sprayed on pictures made in",
A: "chalk and gouache",
B: "graphite and watercolor",
C: "pastel and charcoal",
D: "acry lie and oil color",
answer: "C. pastel and charcoal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The area in a picture that seems to have the greatest visual appeal is the",
A: "central point",
B: "focal point",
C: "colour area",
D: "shaded area",
answer: "B. focal point",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. What does the prevalence of animals in the prehistoric cave paintings reveal",
A: "The caveman’s ability to draw animal forms.",
B: "The caveman’s desire to domesticate wild animals",
C: "The caveman’s inability to draw human forms",
D: "The importance of animals in those societies",
answer: "D. The importance of animals in those societies",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The art which depicts recognizable natural forms is referred to as",
A: "abstract",
B: "calligraphy",
C: "geometric",
D: "figurative",
answer: "D. figurative",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Islamic art has always been restricted to",
A: "geometric ornament and calligraphy",
B: "text writing and sculpture",
C: "calligraphy and block lette4ring",
D: "figurative ornament and calligraphy",
answer: "A. geometric ornament and calligraphy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Who is the exponent of cubism?",
A: "Michelangelo",
B: "Paul Cezanne",
C: "Pablo Picasso",
D: "Vincent Van Gogh",
answer: "C. Pablo Picasso",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The sphinx is a colossal stature with a human head and the body of a",
A: "leopard",
B: "jackal",
C: "camel",
D: "lion",
answer: "D. lion",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The artist sharpens his creative ability if he produces",
A: "airport art",
B: "stereotyped art",
C: "mechanically produced art",
D: "inspiration triggered art",
answer: "D. inspiration triggered art",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. How are elements of design identified in nature?",
A: "Dots, shapes, weights and lines",
B: "Unity, form, harmony and shapes",
C: "Colours, hues, polychrome and monochrome",
D: "Pebbles, trees, rivers and fruits",
answer: "A. Dots, shapes, weights, and lines",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. By what means is illusion of distance created with colour when drawing objects and scenes?",
A: "total gradation",
B: "converging lines",
C: "overlapping",
D: "isolation",
answer: "A. total gradation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A printed notice which serves as a means of communication is termed",
A: "cartoon",
B: "emblem",
C: "pattern",
D: "poster",
answer: "D. poster",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. In indigenous art, there is no distinction between",
A: "verbal and visual art",
B: "art and craft",
C: "fine and commercial art",
D: "painting and sculpture",
answer: "B. art and craft",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Tonal drawing is used to define",
A: "form",
B: "rhythm",
C: "silhouette",
D: "style",
answer: "A. form",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The ancient Egyptian painted beautifully on wooden panels, walls of temples and",
A: "canvas",
B: "leather",
C: "marbles",
D: "papyrus",
answer: "D. papyrus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following ethnic groups is noted for terra cotta sculpture?",
A: "Asante",
B: "Dogon",
C: "Mende",
D: "Nok",
answer: "D. Nok",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Rites of passage mark the transition through",
A: "adulthood, adolescence and old age",
B: "birth, marriage and death",
C: "ancestor ship, chieftaincy and kingship",
D: "infancy, motherhood and parenthood",
answer: "B. birth, marriage, and death",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In architecture, the Greeks invented the",
A: "pyramid",
B: "Doric style",
C: "Sphinx",
D: "sanchi stupa",
answer: "B. Doric style",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Taking inventory of a work of art means stating",
A: "the technical qualities",
B: "the title, date and size of the work",
C: "all the items seen in the work",
D: "methods used by the artist",
answer: "B. the title, date, and size of the work",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. In the practice of animism snakes crocodile’s frogs and birds are linked with",
A: "abundance",
B: "fertility",
C: "growth",
D: "twins",
answer: "B. fertility",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Ancient Egyptians painted women differently from men by making the women",
A: "gorgeous and elegant",
B: "fat and round",
C: "slim and tall",
D: "smaller and lighter",
answer: "D. smaller and lighter",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Bleaching is a process of rendering a fabric",
A: "Dark",
B: "Strong",
C: "Hard",
D: "White",
answer: "D. White",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Lino is the most suitable medium for",
A: "engraving",
B: "etching",
C: "marbling",
D: "print making",
answer: "D. print making",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A mixture of clay and other ceramic materials is called",
A: "body",
B: "batt",
C: "biscuit",
D: "grog",
answer: "A. body",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. All the following are complementary colours except",
A: "red and green",
B: "blue and red",
C: "orange and blue",
D: "red-orange and blue-green",
answer: "B. blue and red",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Passing judgment on a work of art after considering its qualities is termed",
A: "appreciation",
B: "creativity",
C: "criticism",
D: "value",
answer: "C. criticism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The sculpture who executed the discus thrower was",
A: "Kritios",
B: "Myron",
C: "Phaidas",
D: "Praxiteles",
answer: "B. Myron",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. When shading a drawing, consideration should be given to the",
A: "angles of view of the artist",
B: "station point of the artist",
C: "relative size of objects",
D: "direction of light",
answer: "D. direction of light",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following art forms requires the use of odds and ends?",
A: "cartoon",
B: "collage",
C: "fresco",
D: "mosaic",
answer: "B. collage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following masks is used in rituals connected with the Simo society?",
A: "Bundu",
B: "Nimba",
C: "Gelede",
D: "Kanaga",
answer: "A. Bundu",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. In printing fabrics, dyes are fixed to prevent",
A: "bleeding",
B: "blotting",
C: "creeping",
D: "running",
answer: "A. bleeding",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]